<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
  <!--HelpActivity FAQs-->
  <string name="faq">FAQs</string>
  <string name="faq1"><b>Why is root or ADB shell access required?</b></string>
  <string name="faq1_ans">Android won\'t let user apps change manifest permissions and AppOps. Reading AppOps
    without root or ADB is possible provided that hidden APIs are not blacklisted on your device, which is
    <a href="https://developer.android.com/distribute/best-practices/develop/restrictions-non-sdk-interfaces">very unlikely</a>
    on Android 9+.\nThat\'s why we run a separate daemon with high privileges to circumvent the restrictions.\nBy
    default daemon is run with ADB UID (2000) or (if rooted) System UID (1000). However on some ROMs the ADB
    functionality might be crippled usually due to lacking permissions.\nOn rooted devices UID can be changed
    in <b><i>Advanced Settings</i></b>.
  </string>
  <string name="faq2"><b>How to enable ADB over network?</b></string>
  <string name="faq2_ans">Some devices have that setting in <i>Developer Options</i>. On others you
    need to run <i>adb tcpip 5555</i> command from a PC with the device connected through USB.\nFor
    more details see <a href="https://developer.android.com/studio/command-line/adb#wireless">this</a>
    and <a href="https://android.stackexchange.com/a/216474">this</a>.
  </string>
  <string name="faq3"><b>Why are GET_APP_OPS_STATS and INTERNET permissions required?</b></string>
  <string name="faq3_ans">GET_APP_OPS_STATS is required to read AppOps provided that hidden APIs
    work.\nINTERNET permission is required to make use of ADB over network. No connections are made
    outside the device.
  </string>
  <string name="faq4"><b>Why don\'t I see XYZ app in packages list?</b></string>
  <string name="faq4_ans">Please check <i>Exclusion Filters</i>. Almost all of the stock Android packages are
    excluded by default. You can exclude/include any package you want from/to visible list.
  </string>
  <string name="faq5"><b>Why don\'t I see XYZ permission in ABC package?</b></string>
  <string name="faq5_ans">Please check <i>Exclusion Filters</i>.</string>
  <string name="faq5_2"><b>Why don\'t I see XYZ AppOps in ABC package?</b></string>
  <string name="faq5_2_ans">Please check <i>Exclusion Filters</i>.\nOr ABC package might not be using
    XYZ operation. You don\'t need to be worried about this.</string>
  <string name="faq6"><b>What are <i>invalid permissions</i> in Exclusion Filters?</b></string>
  <string name="faq6_ans">If an app is requesting a manifest permission but it\'s not declared (provided) by
    Android framework or any of the installed packages, it\'s an invalid permission.
  </string>
  <string name="faq7"><b>What are <i>extra AppOps</i> in Exclusion Filters?</b></string>
  <string name="faq7_ans">Not all AppOps are being used for all installed apps. But you can enforce an
    AppOp to any app. Selected Extra AppOps appear in all apps\' permission lists so that you can set them.
  </string>
  <string name="faq8"><b>Why can\'t I change XYZ permission?</b></string>
  <string name="faq8_ans">Manifest permissions with only <i>Dangerous</i> protection level (and a few others)
    are changeable. AppOps not dependent on some other AppOp are changeable. Additionally some critical
    framework apps are protected; changing them might brick the device.
  </string>
  <string name="faq9"><b>How to use the app in secondary profile / multi-user environment?</b></string>
  <string name="faq9_ans">Install the app for every profile / user separately. Preferences, reference states,
    backup / restore, everything in every profile works independent of the other profiles.\nOn rooted
    device make sure that root is allowed to profiles / users other than owner / primary user. E.g.
    in case of Magisk set <i>Multiuser Mode</i> to <i>Device Owner Managed</i>.
  </string>
  <string name="faq10"><b>What are different AppOps modes and which should I use?</b></string>
  <string name="faq10_ans">Normally you should <i>Allow</i> or <i>Ignore</i>. Or you may want to
    allow an operation only when the app is in <i>Foreground</i> (only on Pie+). <i>Deny</i> is
    the intense version of <i>Ignore</i> which may crash the requesting app. <i>Default</i> is the
    system\'s default behavior which differs for different AppOps.\nOfficial documentation:
    <a href="https://developer.android.com/reference/android/app/AppOpsManager#access-control">AppOpsManager</a>.
  </string>

  <!--HelpActivity Permission References-->
  <string name="perm_references">Permission References</string>
  <string name="perm_reference_help1">You can set a reference value for permission which can be backed up
    and restored on ROM change or device change.
    So it takes only a few moments to look at all installed packages and figure out which permissions aren\'t
    correctly set. Long press a permission to set or clear its reference state.
  </string>
  <string name="perm_reference_help2"><font color="#FFC107"><b>Orange</b></font>
    state indicates that no reference value is set
  </string>
  <string name="perm_reference_help3"><font color="#00FF00"><b>Green</b></font>
    indicates that reference value matches currently set value
  </string>
  <string name="perm_reference_help4"><font color="#FF0000"><b>Red</b></font>
    indicates that reference value and set value differ
  </string>

  <!--HelpActivity Packages-->
  <string name="package_help1">Colored strip at left indicates <b>reference state</b></string>
  <string name="package_help2">First line shows package <b>label</b></string>
  <string name="package_help3">Second line shows package <b>name</b> and <b>UID</b></string>
  <string name="package_help4">Third line (optionally) shows package\'s state:
    <b>Critical</b> (Framework), <b>Framework</b> or <b>System</b> app.
    Also if the app is <b>Disabled</b>. No state is shown for <b>Enabled</b>, <b>User</b> apps.
  </string>
  <string name="package_help5">Last line shows <b>count</b> of visible manifest permissions out of
    total manifest permissions. And visible AppOps permissions out of total AppOps permissions.
    Invisible permissions are those excluded by applied filters.
  </string>

  <!--HelpActivity Permissions-->
  <string name="perm_help1">Colored strip at left indicates <b>reference state</b></string>
  <string name="perm_help2">First line shows <b>permission name</b></string>
  <string name="perm_help3">Second line shows permission\'s
    <a href="https://developer.android.com/reference/android/R.attr#protectionLevel">protection level</a>:
    <b>Normal</b>, <b>Dangerous</b>, <b>Signature</b>, <b>Development</b>, <b>Privileged</b>,
    <b>Fixed</b>, <b>AppOps</b> or <b>Unknown</b>.
    Also if AppOp is <b>per Package</b> or <b>per UID</b>.
    And if it is an <b>Extra</b> AppOp (never excluded in filter settings).
  </string>
  <string name="perm_help4">Third line (in case of AppOp) shows <b>last access time</b></string>
  <string name="perm_help5">Fourth line (in case of AppOp) shows the referenced value if
    it doesn\'t match the current set value.
  </string>
  <string name="perm_help6">If an AppOp is never set,
    word: <b><i>Default</i></b> is shown below currently set value.
  </string>

  <!--HelpActivity Search-->
  <string name="search_help1">Normally package label, name and UID are searched from visible
    list.\nWith deep search permission name and other parameters are queried.\nNote that exclusion
    filters are effective when making search.\nYou can use the following special keywords in search:
  </string>
  <string name="search_help2">App state:\n
    <b><i>:Critical :Framework :System :User :Disabled</i></b>
  </string>
  <string name="search_help3">Reference state:\n
    <b><i>:ORANGE :GREEN :RED</i></b>
  </string>
  <string name="search_help4">Permissions protection level:\n
    <b><i>:Normal :Dangerous :Signature</i></b>\n
    <b><i>:Development :Privileged :Fixed</i></b>\n
    <b><i>:AppOps :Unknown</i></b>
  </string>
  <string name="search_help5">Per UID AppOps:\n
    <b><i>:UID</i></b>
  </string>
  <string name="search_help6">AppOps with last access time:\n
    <b><i>:TIME</i></b>
  </string>
  <string name="search_help7">Extra AppOps (never excluded in filter settings):\n
    <b><i>:Extra</i></b>
  </string>
  <string name="search_help8">&amp; (AND) and | (OR) operators:\n
    <b><i>Foo|Bar&amp;Baz</i></b>
  </string>
</resources>
